you've probably heard of the Pythagorean
theorem a squared plus b squared equals
c squared but what is it actually and
why is it true let's draw this out A and
B are these two sides and C is the
hypotenuse if you squared say the
hypotenuse then you would get the area
of a square with a side length C the
Pythagorean theorem states that for any
right angle triangle the square of the
hypotenuse C is equal to the sum of the
squared of the other two sides A and B
also called the feet but don't just take
my word for it let's prove it using a
visual proof this is a right triangle
these are four identical right triangles
you can arrange them in a way that they
form a square of side length a plus b as
you can see from the side length the
square in the top left has an area of a
squared and the one in the bottom left
has one of B squared however these
triangles can be rearranged to form an
identical square of side length a plus b
now however the middle square has formed
an area of c squared hence from this
proof a squared plus b squared equals c
squared now there are many other
numerical ways to prove this however I
find this visual proof so elegant hope
you've learned something stay curious
and I'll see you in the next one